<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Total Sweet - News</title>
  <updated>2023-03-09T16:41:09+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Total Sweet</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-for-the-win</id>
    <published>2023-03-09T16:41:09+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T16:41:09+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-for-the-win"/>
    <title>Xylitol for the win</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p> We have seen an increase in the number of articles highlighting the risks associated with artificial sweetener recently. </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Screenshot_2023-03-09_at_16.36.11_600x600.png?v=1678379832" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p> <strong>Erythritol: artificial sweetener linked to higher risk of heart attack</strong></p>
<p>https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/20950a26-bc5a-11ed-b039-425ba6c60d6d?shareToken=5d0d7e013cbe9aeb0a14ebb2939c12a3</p>
<p><strong>Low Calorie Sweetener may raise the risks of heart attacks and strokes, study warns:</strong></p>
<p>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-11798339/Artificial-low-calorie-sweetener-raise-heart-attack-stroke-risk.html</p>
<h3>We are proud to say that Xylitol has been around for over 100 years and has more than 1,500 research articles proving both its benefits and safety. We have listed plenty of these <a href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/pages/studies-of-interest">HERE</a> for you.</h3>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/quinoa-salad-with-avocado-mango-and-pomegranate</id>
    <published>2023-03-09T14:00:03+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:00:03+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/quinoa-salad-with-avocado-mango-and-pomegranate"/>
    <title>Quinoa Salad with Avocado, Mango and Pomegranate</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/total-sweet-xylitol-salad-recipe_600x600.jpg?v=1678370086" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>This stunning dish was created for Total Sweet Xylitol by The Food Effect Doctor (<a href="https://www.thefoodeffect.co.uk/?fbclid=IwAR23VGim42bKa_hWWTQx0FMJnN7p8GWGDwHX5NqqiigFfoLZFo_l1-bUUF4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.thefoodeffect.co.uk/</a>) as side dish for a festive meal, but, with summer approaching, it also makes a delicious<span> </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/hashtag/vegan?__eep__=6&amp;__cft__%5b0%5d=AZWseMRdFBk5h5PqEV0vC-fGoHhs2D7HPl9sbJ0EULsOR-RV3OlhbfO3uXWGmIvSVs5BDpDeWDYxWLGb5jtvsFZK2hEymB94sjjlUBDBW9C9ZcNWYuH2aMBCjzGKp7HecDZz8gjCOxI2oHYJoUL_akx5kISAbOTlKm0hwTKN8OjjCup0cfWoShT30mv5_E5XnMs&amp;__tn__=*NK-R">#vegan</a><span> </span>light lunch. Hopefully the sun will shine this weekend and we can enjoy its fresh and exciting flavours.</p>
<p><b>Ingredients</b></p>
<p>Serves 2 as a main course, 4 as a side dish</p>
<p>• 170g uncooked red quinoa (or regular white quinoa)</p>
<p>• 1 ripe avocado, diced</p>
<p>• 1 small ripe mango, peeled and diced</p>
<p>• 80g pomegranate seeds</p>
<p>• 20g pistachio nuts, shelled</p>
<p>• 4 spring onions, thinly sliced</p>
<p>• A few handfuls of spinach or salad leaves</p>
<p><strong>For the dressing</strong></p>
<p>• 1 tbsp olive oil</p>
<p>• 2 tbsp balsamic vinegar</p>
<p>• 1 tsp sesame oil</p>
<p>• 2 tsp low sodium soya sauce</p>
<p><b>Method</b></p>
<p>Cook the quinoa according to the packet instructions. Allow to cool slightly. Put all the salad ingredients in a large bowl. Whisk together the dressing ingredients. Add to the salad, and toss well to coat.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/delicious-recipes-from-phil-vickery</id>
    <published>2022-10-12T16:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:59:09+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/delicious-recipes-from-phil-vickery"/>
    <title>Delicious recipes from Phil Vickery</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="lead"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/ricotta-doughnuts-web-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678377529" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p class="lead">Phil Vickery's recipes are a real hit, and this month we are very pleased to see them appear across several of our favourite magazine titles.</p>
<p>Here are some links to find out more...</p>
<p>Check out a full interview with Phil here and see what he thinks to using xylitol in his cooking:  <a href="http://www.vegetarianliving.co.uk/interviews.php?do=view&amp;article=199">http://www.vegetarianliving.co.uk/interviews.php?do=view&amp;article=199</a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodthingsmagazine.com/phil-vickerys-blueberry-trifle/">http://goodthingsmagazine.com/phil-vickerys-blueberry-trifle/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.foodheavenmag.com/rich-chocolate-orange-tart-raspberry-sauce/">http://www.foodheavenmag.com/rich-chocolate-orange-tart-raspberry-sauce/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.freefromheaven.com/2017/05/phil-vickerys-sweet-gluten-free-ricotta-doughnut-recipe/">http://www.freefromheaven.com/2017/05/phil-vickerys-sweet-gluten-free-ricotta-doughnut-recipe/</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/balancing-glucose-levels</id>
    <published>2022-04-04T17:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T16:44:02+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/balancing-glucose-levels"/>
    <title>Balancing Glucose Levels</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Balancing_Glucose_Levels_2048x2048.png?v=1667255247" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<h2>How you can still enjoy carbs and sweet tastes while losing weight with Total Sweet®?</h2>
<p>Many of us struggle with dieting and think counting calories and cutting out carbs will help with weight loss. According to biochemist Jessie Inchauspé, simply eating food in a different order and balancing your blood glucose levels is an effective way to lose weight and gain energy<sup>1</sup>. </p>
<p>Insulin makes the route to our fat cells a one-way street, so weight loss becomes doubly tricky. But if our glucose levels, and therefore our insulin levels, are steady, we shed pounds. In a 2021 study of 5,600 people, Canadian scientists showed that weight loss is always preceded by insulin decrease<sup>2</sup> and Inchauspé indicates how a simple change can effect this. </p>
<p>Eating veggies first, proteins second, and carbs last slows down the digestive process and reduces the effect of carbs on blood sugar levels<sup>3</sup>. Eating in this order means you can still enjoy a good sandwich and look forward to a bowl of pasta! But what about when you fancy something sweet? Well, we’ve got another solution. </p>
<p>With <strong>Total Sweet®</strong>, you can keep your blood sugar level steady whilst still consuming sweet flavours. <em>Total Sweet</em> is a natural alternative to sugar made solely from naturally occurring xylitol from European birch and beech wood. Xylitol contains zero fructose and has a glycemic index (GI) of 7 - meaning <em>Total Sweet</em> has a negligible effect on blood sugar and insulin<sup>4</sup>. It can be used as a substitute for sugar in nearly any recipe with a 1:1 conversion. So now you can add a little sweetness to your food guilt-free without worrying about spiking your glucose levels.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/health-risk-associated-with-artificial-sweeteners</id>
    <published>2022-03-21T17:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T16:43:43+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/health-risk-associated-with-artificial-sweeteners"/>
    <title>Health Risk Associated with Artificial Sweeteners?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Health_Risk_Associated_with_Artificial_Sweeteners_2048x2048.png?v=1667255092" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 class="lead">As a new study appears to highlight the health risks associated with artificial sweeteners, what’s the alternative?</h2>
<p>The debate regarding artificial sweeteners and health risks has been heating up.</p>
<p>A recent large-scale study from the French National Institute for Health and Medical Research and Sorbonne Paris Nord University reported a 13% higher rise of cancer risk for people who consumed large quantities of artificial sweeteners.</p>
<p>Tracking 100,000 people over 8 years, they observed the highest risk sweeteners were aspartame and acesulfame-K, both used in the UK in soft drinks like Diet Coke, as well as products like yogurts and even cheese</p>
<p>However, independent UK experts claim the study does not prove, or even suggest, we should go back to sugar and turn our backs on artificial sweeteners2. All sweeteners in the EU undergo a safety assessment by the European Food Safety Authority (EFSA) before being allowed to be used in any food and drink.</p>
<p>For those choosing to cut back on sugar but concerned about switching to artificial sweeteners, the science backs Xylitol as a safe natural sugar alternative. Total Sweet® xylitol is made solely from natural European birch and beech wood. Xylitol is EFSA approved3 and helps control blood sugar levels (with a GI value of just 7) making it suitable for diabetics too, as well as being good for bones and teeth. It is also easy to use, as it can be used as a substitute for sugar in nearly any recipe with a 1:1 conversion and tastes just like sugar.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/did-you-know</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T16:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-02-01T15:59:19+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/did-you-know"/>
    <title>Did you know.....</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/no-bakechocolatetart-w555h350_2048x2048.png?v=1667255421" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 class="lead">...we have a massive back catalogue of downloadable recipes on our website? Here is one of our favourites!</h2>
<p>This ridiculously good no-bake chocolate tart features a layer of hazelnut butterscotch, made with xylitol (Total Sweet) instead of sugar, and a layer of chocolate ganache. The perfect guilt-free(ish) dessert, that is diabetes-friendly</p>
<p><b><u>Ingredients:</u></b><span> </span><b>Tart crust:</b><span> </span>200g rolled oats  2tbsp Total Sweet Xylitol  1tbsp cocoa powder 100g butter, melted <span> </span><b>Hazelnut butterscotch:</b><span> </span>70g butter  170g Total Sweet Xylitol  100ml double cream 100g hazelnut toasted  1/4tsp sea salt <span> </span><b>Chocolate ganache</b>: 170g dark chocolate, chopped (unsweetened preferably) 200ml double cream 3tbsp Total Sweet Xylitol. (Only if unsweetened chocolate is used)</p>
<p><b><u>Method:</u></b><span> </span><b>Crust:</b><span> </span>Combine oats with Total Sweet Xylitol &amp; cocoa powder in a food processor until it becomes coarse. Then add melted butter, and pulse until the mixture sticks together. Transfer the mixture to a 9” tart pan and press firmly to create an even tart shell. Refrigerate for at least 1 hr. <span> </span><b>Butterscotch:</b><span> </span>Melt butter in a medium-size saucepan and add sea salt &amp; Total Sweet Xylitol. Cook over a medium heat whilst stirring for about 10 mins, or until golden brown. Remove from heat, add double cream, and stir until well combined. Set aside to cool for at least 20 mins.  Meanwhile, grind the toasted hazelnuts until coarse. Mix with the butterscotch until well combined.  Pour the mixture onto the oat base and refrigerate for 20 mins. <span> </span><b>Chocolate Ganache:</b><span> </span>Heat the double cream in a small saucepan until almost boiling. Add the chocolate and Total Sweet Xylitol (if you’re using unsweetened chocolate) and stir it until all the chocolate has melted, and the mixture is smooth.  Pour it over the butterscotch layer and pop in the fridge to set.  Remove from fridge 10 mins before serving. Slice and enjoy!! </p>
<p><b>Note:</b>    This delicious tart was created by Niushacooks using Total Sweet Xylitol.  Total Sweet is so easy to use as a replacement to sugar – simply use 1 for 1 in recipes, and instantly reduce your sugar spikes and calories… along with actively preventing the build-up of bacteria that can cause tooth decay.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/national-tree-week</id>
    <published>2021-12-10T16:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-02-01T15:59:53+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/national-tree-week"/>
    <title>National tree Week</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/birch-leaves-national-tree-week_2048x2048.png?v=1667255565" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 class="lead">Did you know that Total Sweet is made from the bark of sustainably sourced European birch and beech trees?</h2>
<p>National Tree Week is the UK’s biggest annual tree celebration. This year it takes place from the 27 November to the 5 December – coinciding perfectly with the start of tree planting season. </p>
<p>2021 saw world leaders commit to ending deforestation by 2030, marking the start of a worldwide commitment to greenery. National Tree Week will see thousands of participants planting, studying, and educating. </p>
<p>To tackle deforestation effectively, we need to identify the causes – rather than just remedying the symptoms. Tree planting initiatives are great, but they’re only effective when we commit to eliminating unsustainable farming and harvest methods. The data shows that business is a driving force behind these unsustainable methods.</p>
<p>Leading UK sugar alternative <b>Total Sweet® </b>has a lot to thank trees for. The product is made from the bark of sustainably sourced European birch and beech trees. We have scoured the earth for the most sustainable raw material available and are delighted that our production methods use 93% less land, create 80% less greenhouse gas emissions and have a 90% smaller blue water footprint than cheaper Asian xylitol does. Being mindful of and giving back to the environment is important to <i>Total Sweet</i>, which is why they have partnered with SEED Madagascar to help replant trees in badly affected areas and allow the Lemur populations to reconnect in areas where they have been cut off from the forest due to excess deforestation. </p>
<p>To date, <i>Total Sweet</i> have planted over 60,000 trees. Which means more tasty xylitol, and a brighter greener future. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/festive-drinks-with-one-wicked-twist</id>
    <published>2021-12-09T16:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-02-01T15:58:51+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/festive-drinks-with-one-wicked-twist"/>
    <title>Festive drinks with one wicked twist....</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Festive_Drinks_Sugar_Free_2048x2048.jpg?v=1667255729" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h2 class="lead">Ditch high sugar hot drinks, and opt for festive totally sweet alternatives</h2>
<p>Festive treats are part of what makes Christmas special. It’s a chance to overindulge (and overspend) in seasonally delicious hot drinks, and fruity little pies.</p>
<p>Famous coffee chains flood our palettes with festive alternatives to familiar favourites.  From peppermint hot chocolate to gingerbread latte, toffee frothy makes to whipped cream and all the extras coffee.</p>
<p>Whilst they look (and taste) utterly inviting, they are nearly always flavoured and sweetened with syrups high in refined sugar.  The new Quality Street Toffee Penny Latte with Light Dairy Swirl (from Costa Coffee) contains 40.1g of sugar in a 379ml drink – the same as 4 regular donuts. </p>
<p>To cut down on refined sugar <u>and</u> cut down on spending, why not try a calorie friendly swap without sacrificing any taste on your favourite take-away drinks.</p>
<p><strong>Total Sweet®</strong> is the UK’s leading xylitol brand, established in 2005.  <em>Total Sweet</em> is a natural sugar alternative that looks, feels and tastes just like sugar. <em>Total Sweet</em> can be used in place of sugar in nearly any recipe and contains 40% less calories than sugar, just replace it like for like with sugar.  </p>
<p>Try combining cinnamon, nutmeg, ginger, milk, with <em>Total Sweet</em> and allspice over a low heat for a sweet winter warmer minus the refined sugar.</p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/when-life-gives-you-lemons</id>
    <published>2021-12-07T13:30:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:25:22+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/when-life-gives-you-lemons"/>
    <title>When Life gives you Lemons</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="lead" style="text-align: center;"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/istockphoto-663568532-612x612_600x600.jpg?v=1678367978" alt=""></p>
<p class="lead"> </p>
<p class="lead">The humble lemon makes the ‘diabetic superfoods’ list. Here is how Total Sweet is the perfect partner...</p>
<p><em>When life gives you lemons… you can make lemonade;</em> <em><strong>OR</strong></em> use it to help control your blood sugar levels. </p>
<p>Studies into the effect of different foods on blood sugar levels [1] show how sugar levels in our diets have profound effects, especially on those with Diabetes.</p>
<p>Sugar kickstarts an insulin response within our bodies. Insulin helps your body bring sugars into its cells, providing energy. Diabetics often have a harder time with this natural process, which can lead to numerous health issues. </p>
<p>Type 2 Diabetics can still produce insulin, but the body uses this insulin incorrectly, making blood sugars hard to regulate. This is where our trusty lemon comes in. One study found that lemon peels may prevent sugar absorption into the blood [1]. They can also lower glucose levels, reduce insulin resistance, and regulate your metabolism. A different study also concluded that lemons helped to lower obesity in rodents. And as obesity is heavily linked to the onset of Type 2 Diabetes, it’s the perfect reason to show lemons the love [2]. </p>
<p>The American Diabetes Association include lemons on their list of ‘<strong>diabetic superfoods</strong>’. And while oranges also made the cut, ‘lemon peel essential oil exhibited higher antidiabetic and antihypertensive activities compared to orange peels’ [3]. </p>
<p>With science confirming the link between blood sugar levels and lemon consumption, you may be wondering how to incorporate more of it into your diet. </p>
<p>Lemons are versatile, so using them in hot and cold drinks and your favourite recipes will be a breeze. Here’s a couple of ways we’ve found to get more lemons into your diet.  After all, zest is best: </p>
<ul>
<li>Make your own natural lemonade using fresh lemons, sparkling or soda water and <strong>Total Sweet® </strong>- no added sugar!</li>
<li>Add fresh lemon zest to pasta sauces, salads, and seasonings. Chinese style lemon chicken anyone? </li>
<li>Stir lemon puree into natural yoghurt… and add a hint of natural sweetness with <em>Total Sweet.</em>
</li>
<li>Add small chunks of lemon to your water bottles…for a refreshing twist on hydrating.</li>
<li>When cooking with fish, add a few fresh lemon slices to the top to help extract the essential oils.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>The combination of sweet and sour goes great in many tart desserts. Try mixing fresh lemon puree with <em>Total Sweet</em> for a refreshingly punchy mix perfect for adding to cake mixes and sauces. Want to bake your favourite recipes with <em>Total Sweet</em>? Easy peezy. Simply replace the sugar with <em>Total Sweet</em>, 1:1, with no complicated conversions!</p>
<p>Try homemade lemon marmalade using lemons and <em>Total Sweet</em> for a fresh breakfast toast topper created to put a spring in your step.</p>
<p>Even if you aren’t diabetic or dieting, lemons still have a part to play in a healthy lifestyle. Lemons are packed full of good stuff, from vitamins c and d to antioxidants and calcium. Vitamin C has been shown to play a protective role in the development of Type 2 Diabetes [4], making lemons an ideal source. So, if you’re asking whether the juice is worth the squeeze, we can assure you that it certainly is. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong>  As always, make sure to consult a medical professional before jumping into the world of citrus. Everybody is different, and while calls to invest in the zest may work for some of us, others may not benefit in the same way. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>[1] Inhibition of enzymes linked to type-2 diabetes and hypertension by essential oils from peels of orange and lemon. <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10942912.2017.1303709">https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10942912.2017.1303709</a></p>
<p>[2] Citrange Fruit Extracts Alleviate Obesity-Associated Metabolic Disorder in High-Fat Diet-Induced Obese C57BL/6 Mous. <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/1422-0067/14/12/23736/htm">https://www.mdpi.com/1422-0067/14/12/23736/htm</a></p>
<p>[3] What superstar foods are good for diabetes? <a href="https://www.diabetes.org/healthy-living/recipes-nutrition/eating-well/diabetes-superstar-foods">https://www.diabetes.org/healthy-living/recipes-nutrition/eating-well/diabetes-superstar-foods</a></p>
<p>[4] Dietary Vitamin C Intake Reduces the Risk of Type 2 Diabetes in Chinese Adults: HOMA-IR and T-AOC as Potential Mediators. <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0163571">https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0163571</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/popeye-could-have-been-on-to-something</id>
    <published>2021-06-25T14:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:40:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/popeye-could-have-been-on-to-something"/>
    <title>Popeye could have been on to something...!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Total_Sweet_Xylitol_Spinach_popeye_600x600.jpg?v=1678368452" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Here at Total Sweet Xylitol we're always on the look out for new and exciting research on nutrition and we discovered an interesting article this morning...</p>
<p>We normally think about protein when it comes to nutrition for strengthening muscles, but this piece discusses the possibility that leafy greens could help build muscle strength. Definitely worth a read if you're at all interested in performance linked nutrition.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cleaneatingmag.com/clean-diet/food-health-news/build-stronger-muscles-by-eating-more-greens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.cleaneatingmag.com/</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/jam-making-time</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T14:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:39:48+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/jam-making-time"/>
    <title>Jam making time</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/raspberry-jam-total-sweet-xylitol-blog_600x600.jpg?v=1678369157" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We're counting down the days until our first fruits are ready to pick. As soon as they are, we'll be</p>
<p> making a few pots of jam, using Total Sweet Xylitol instead of sugar. We've got a couple of different recipes on the website, but this<span> </span><a href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/recipes/easy-raspberry-jam">raspberry one<span> </span></a>from Stacey Hart (Great British Bake Off semi-finalist) is a favourite. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/weight-loss-tips-from-christine-bailey</id>
    <published>2021-06-11T14:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:43:23+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/weight-loss-tips-from-christine-bailey"/>
    <title>Weight loss tips from Christine Bailey</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/scales-1-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678369356" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p> </p>
<p><span>An interesting read, for anyone looking to lose a few pounds, from The Metro this week. The tips in the piece are from a great nutritionist called </span><a href="https://www.christinebailey.co.uk/">Christine Bailey</a><span> and feature everything from xylitol to sleep. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://metro.co.uk/2021/06/09/lose-weight-the-healthy-way-with-these-basic-rules-14738088/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>https://metro.co.uk/</span></a></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/ice-cream-time</id>
    <published>2021-06-04T14:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:50:02+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/ice-cream-time"/>
    <title>Ice cream time!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Total-sweet-xylitol-daily-mail_600x600.png?v=1678369785" alt=""></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>It looks like we'll be seeing hot weather into next week, so make sure you're topped up with ice cream. A couple of our favourites, which just so happen to contain xylitol, were ranked highly in this review...</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-7250599/Dietitian-tests-called-healthy-ice-creams.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.dailymail.co.uk/health</a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Check in next week when we'll be sharing some of our favourite summer recipes with you.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/the-simples-things</id>
    <published>2021-06-02T13:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T13:40:44+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/the-simples-things"/>
    <title>The simple things..</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/Sprinkle_Total_Sweet_on_Strawberries_600x600.jpg?v=1678368219" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Sometimes it's the little things in life...like sitting back on a sunny day with a handful of strawberries sprinkled with just a little Total Sweet Xylitol. </p>
<p>We've still got plenty of strawberries to pick, so looking forward to a scrumptious weekend and hoping the sun shines.</p>
<p>Have a great weekend everyone.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/national-cherry-cobbler-day</id>
    <published>2021-05-17T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:35:53+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/national-cherry-cobbler-day"/>
    <title>National Cherry Cobbler Day</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/sweet-cherry-cobbler-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678372455" alt="" style="float: none;"></div>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<div class="rich-text">
<p>There seems to be a 'day' for everything and apparently today is National Cherry Cobbler Day. Cobbler's aren't something we make much of here, so it seems a good reason to give one a go.</p>
<p>We're going to try this recipe, but swapping the sugar for Total Sweet Xylitol to help bring the sugar content down. If you're counting your sugar intake, don't forget to include that found in the cherries and other ingredients.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.simplyrecipes.com/recipes/sweet_cherry_cobbler/">https://www.simplyrecipes.com/</a></p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/mental-health-awareness-week</id>
    <published>2021-05-10T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:38:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/mental-health-awareness-week"/>
    <title>Mental Health Awareness Week</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/mental-health-awareness-week-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678372665" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Today is the start of #MentalHealthAwarenessWeek</p>
<p>Sometimes it's hard for Total Sweet Xylitol, as a brand in the health food arena, to get the balance right between being pushy and demonizing certain foods and letting people know that it's ok not to have the 'prefect' diet.</p>
<p>This week we'd like to focus on celebrating each other and how we're not perfect and that that's ok. None of us has the perfect diet, in fact it's almost certain that no one knows what the perfect diet is, and what works for one person might not work for the next. So if you reach for that extra piece of cake, don't beat yourself up about it. Enjoy it and move on :-) </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/limited-lemurs</id>
    <published>2021-04-26T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:43:22+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/limited-lemurs"/>
    <title>Limited Lemurs</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/lemur-print-website-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678372959" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Last year total sweet xylitol sponsored a tree nursery for Project Ala, which is planting tree corridors on Madagascar to help the movement of lemurs and other endangered wildlife.</p>
<p>To help raise more important funds for the project Seed Madagascar have 50 of these amazing limited prints to give to those who pledge funds to the project...</p>
<p>Whilst most of us will recognise Madagascar’s famous ring tailed lemurs, it’s one of the island’s lesser known species that is the subject for this limited edition print by artist<span> </span><a href="https://www.louisemiller.me/">Louise Miller</a>.</p>
<p>The Tanosi Mouse Lemur, depicted in the print, was only announced as a species in 2013. However, this tiny lemur is already endangered and in need of conservation support, which is what Louise (a renowned artist and animator, who has worked with the likes of MTV, EA Games and Disney) hopes her prints, originally painted in watercolour and ink, will help provide.</p>
<p>50 limited edition framed prints have been produced and will be given to people who pledge £100 (or set up monthly donations of £10) to Project Ala (which means 'forest' in Malagasy). A project run by<span> </span><a href="file:///C:/Users/DanR/Desktop/New%20Chapter/Azafady/madagascar.co.uk">SEED Madagascar</a>, one of Project Ala’s main aims is to create forest corridors between existing pockets of habitat for lemurs (including The Tanosi Mouse Lemur) and other endangered wildlife on Madagascar. Planting tree corridors between segmented pieces of forest allows lemurs to move more freely again and hopefully breed and increase in numbers.</p>
<p>To find out how you can support the project and become the owner of one of these very special prints, please visit<span> </span><a href="http://www.madagascar.co.uk/">www.madagascar.co.uk</a></p>
<p>SEED Madagascar would like to thank Louise, Kellmatt printers and Photo Frames &amp; Art for their support.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/dental-care</id>
    <published>2021-04-20T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:46:09+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/dental-care"/>
    <title>Dental care</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/woman-brushing-teeth-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678373129" alt=""></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Hopefully, if you use Total Sweet Xylitol regularly, you'll know it's good for your teeth (if not click </span><a href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/pages/dental">here</a><span> to find out more), but do you know how to look after your toothbrush properly? If not, you mind find this article, from the Independent's website, interesting - </span><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/this-is-how-often-you-should-replace-your-toothbrush-b1832692.html">https://www.independent.co.uk/...</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-and-diabetes</id>
    <published>2021-03-26T15:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:55:40+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-and-diabetes"/>
    <title>Xylitol and diabetes*</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We get asked a lot about xylitol and diabetes*. Here's a little information, which may help...</p>
<p>Xylitol has a glycaemic index (GI) value of around 7, which is about 10 times lower than sugar and 4 times lower than fructose, making it ideal for those with diabetes*, or at risk of developing diabetes, as it has a less dramatic effect on blood glucose levels.</p>
<p>On top of its GI value benefits, xylitol has 40% less calories than sugar and less than half the 'available' carbohydrates, those that are absorbed and used by the body. Furthermore, xylitol is totally natural and boasts a host of other health benefits.</p>
<p>Another huge benefit of Total Sweet for diabetes sufferers is that it can be used in cooking in the same quantities as sugar, meaning it's never been easier to make reduced sugar desserts and other foods.</p>
<p>Furthermore xylitol is seen to actively promote healthy teeth and reduce plaque and dental decay.</p>
<p>* <em>Please note that there are several different types and severities of diabetes. If you are in any way unsure as to whether xylitol is suitable for your particular needs please consult your health advisor or doctor.</em></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/love-food-hate-waste</id>
    <published>2020-10-30T15:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T14:58:41+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/love-food-hate-waste"/>
    <title>Love Food Hate Waste</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/pumpkin-seeds-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678373907" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We enjoy this simple recipe (from Jamie Oliver) every year, around this time. We've normally just finished carving a pumpkin and have a glass of wine in hand. They make a great alternative to crisps or nuts #lovefoodhatewaste.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jamieoliver.com/features/how-to-roast-pumpkin-seeds/">https://www.jamieoliver.com/fe...</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/it-all-starts-with-a-seed</id>
    <published>2020-10-23T15:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:18:31+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/it-all-starts-with-a-seed"/>
    <title>It all starts with a seed</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/plant-corridor-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678374133" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>This year we teamed up with a brilliant charity called <a href="https://madagascar.co.uk/">SEED Madagascar</a> to support them with an initiative called Project Ala (which means 'forest' in Malagasy).</p>
<p>The project aims to plant tree corridors between segmented pieces of forest, which have been split up due to deforestation, and allow lemurs, and other wildlife, to move more freely again and hopefully breed and increase in numbers.</p>
<p>It's great to hear the Project (please see link below) is already having a positive impact on the plants, animals and people of Madagascar:</p>
<p><a href="https://madagascar.co.uk/blog/2020/10/it-all-starts-seed?fbclid=IwAR1xWvyPQaM6RmVwfdBpqXVjH64OyadebiT95t8VejRtLueNCXx26CX2gfc">https://madagascar.co.uk/blog/...</a></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/plant-comparison-w800_600x600.jpg?v=1678374159" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/great-british-food</id>
    <published>2020-09-25T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:05:10+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/great-british-food"/>
    <title>Great British Food</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/great-british-food-total-sweet-autumn-2020-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678374299" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>We're delighted that Total Sweet Xylitol is named as a 'brilliant baking buy' in the latest issue of Great British Food Magazine (</span><a href="https://www.greatbritishfoodawards.com/">https://www.greatbritishfoodaw...</a><span>). The beauty of Total Sweet is that it looks, tastes and feels just like sugar, so (except in a few exceptions, like bread) it can be used in exactly the same way and quantities in baking, to make tasty, healthier desserts. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/eating-for-a-better-complexion</id>
    <published>2020-07-06T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:06:59+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/eating-for-a-better-complexion"/>
    <title>Eating for a better complexion</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/complexion-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678374395" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We found this article, by skincare guru Liz Earle, on how to eat for a better complexion really interesting; and not just because she uses xylitol.</p>
<p>Published by<span> </span><a href="https://www.deliciousmagazine.co.uk/">Delicious Magazine</a></p>
<p><a class="oajrlxb2 g5ia77u1 qu0x051f esr5mh6w e9989ue4 r7d6kgcz rq0escxv nhd2j8a9 nc684nl6 p7hjln8o kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x jb3vyjys rz4wbd8a qt6c0cv9 a8nywdso i1ao9s8h esuyzwwr f1sip0of lzcic4wl py34i1dx gpro0wi8" href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.deliciousmagazine.co.uk%2Fwhat-to-eat-to-improve-your-skin%2F%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR3oXm4ihHLYB5qDrX2RjNQ0MLD4ipmCg_G7xusmtMIYM-DCuRkuQdiSf2k&amp;h=AT2JZDWhcFPitj2xdn6BKBagheD1KdLnfX3gkcZiCiu8vnjH2gLQZCmQ9ODhZ97obs7GPOEcnX1A1y4F99QZVzrSsl5UcJUEzPw6HksB7L6X_dQtDantjR3JuPe1TW0i&amp;__tn__=-UK-R&amp;c%5B0%5D=AT3Rqk3QoHXokbTp2bkE0xLw0PrLqEvT3x2f2Uvu11cMYt6qeMu381JP1p7dTIcAMBg05FEREA1qZn8ievtU0Fl4uqxY2CLhLlRY3-taHCgqsViFm6Odu_8KZ3GdsW6FvEYe5KvbMqAcmywWpkuVHUKb3PjW7QqMVVRdQSFKx-crqK39iXVg3tZmv5EHRRo" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" role="link" target="_blank" tabindex="0">https://www.deliciousmagazine.co.uk/what-to-eat-to-improve-your-skin/</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/salads-in-the-sun</id>
    <published>2020-06-23T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:09:26+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/salads-in-the-sun"/>
    <title>Salads in the sun</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We have no idea why, but salads always taste nicer in the sun. We're looking forward to a bowlful of this stunner, which uses Total Sweet Xylitol, from top nutritionist Christine Bailey.</p>
<p>Published in this month's Vegan Food and Living magazine, where you'll find some more of Christine's recipes.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/vegan-food-and-living-mango-salad-june-2020-w800_600x600.jpg?v=1678374544" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/brain-boosting-brownies</id>
    <published>2020-05-20T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:17:28+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/brain-boosting-brownies"/>
    <title>Brain boosting brownies</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/beetchocolatebrownies1-small-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678375038" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>It's fair to say that the Total Sweet team like chocolate brownies. We like them even more when they could help boost our brain health!</p>
<p>Check out the link below to discover a recipe, containing xylitol, which could help boost your brain health and tastes delicious too.</p>
<p><a href="https://thetaste.ie/wp/beet-chocolate-brownies-recipe-by-christine-bailey/">https://thetaste.ie/wp/beet-chocolate-brownies-recipe-by-christine-bailey/</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/sugar-free-vegan-chocolates</id>
    <published>2020-03-20T15:30:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:25:49+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/sugar-free-vegan-chocolates"/>
    <title>Sugar free vegan chocolates</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/daily-mirror-coverage-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678375521" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Delicious, sugar-free, vegan chocolates! 'It can't be done' I hear you say. Oh yes it can, as this recipe from The Balanced Kitchen, which uses xylitol and was published in yesterday's Daily Mirror, proves.</p>
<p>I think we all deserve to indulge in some at the moment!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/the_balanced_kitchen?fbclid=IwAR1rrFrARS9rGKkkxykts1iCGTRl-5ZGIBQh3an3-mO_rlBp4uEyA364I1k" target="_blank" data-ft='{"tn":"-U"}' rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-lynx-mode="async" data-lynx-uri="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.instagram.com%2Fthe_balanced_kitchen%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR1rrFrARS9rGKkkxykts1iCGTRl-5ZGIBQh3an3-mO_rlBp4uEyA364I1k&amp;h=AT1DmIOAM_MnN0yctSuGCdNv1x1fuH7obNnJC7OcE3_6cw9c7PYzTMmV3SUpqHYw1JTtUgYNJGrvF_nn3NG8rmvgeXx1TBsM3TiviNLwCOx4yCxmjuLDkxKvVELFt86szAcPpC63v0NZe7-v8MSUhxEckKga-9grZAzxkzzgPIIvz7Hl0_SZZkDiER1isbyi52JexAGsKoaBBXDMHbh40t6KFH37Yd5Pkv02_gAei3oSvW4SYl0_zgSzO2im_7cjJB_z_G66A7QqzfJ8U9gpze9Hb28herF4BgjI3L1ib4sYDJNa8GjEYnftU5vKE43qkjc1R0BybF-PARWpfENqgba2CPtde2b_N3NFHoccc6rVGCY_QsYWt2FE4xF4VQaMre4Dh9tfA9hnTyvZJiaZNgs4jSjZ5wVw2rjZGknktpdAKxhz2MZY3_nHzaheKi3-Y1SE7h-o7AMeCCk0wwkp4ANtp85Gyt2P9wYKc6_OwPC4ml8VCD-zyX0Rp4W6X_rfZ3IxbTnzIAzQVvqGvRlpaJpKxqx8tXCa3gdlBwl37skyv_0PaIbCX17TenmZ_S74Z1iiUkooyQyu6mPdxUHMDcDYpLzSaikaLJIWg30UGcN3Txf3hN9-zyklWKAKF5UHOg">www.instagram.com/the_balanced_kitchen</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/why-are-we-still-eating-so-much-sugar</id>
    <published>2019-09-23T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:28:51+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/why-are-we-still-eating-so-much-sugar"/>
    <title>Why are we still eating so much sugar?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/sugar-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678375722" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Despite all the news stories about how sugar is bad for our health, it appears sugar consumption in the UK is still rising - <a href="https://www.nursinginpractice.com/obesity-nutrition/sugar-consumption-rises-england-despite-tax">https://www.nursinginpractice.com/obesity-nutrition/sugar-consumption-rises-england-despite-tax</a></p>
<p>Perhaps it is time for a change in message? Instead of telling people how bad sugar is for them (let's be honest we all know that already) and what they should NOT be eating, why not talk more about the tasty and healthy products we can eat? With products like xylitol now on the market, you can make a cake with very little sugar in it, so can we not spread a more positive message about ways to cut sugar out of your diet without having to make major sacrifices?</p>
<p>Some of our thoughts for the day.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-icing-sugar</id>
    <published>2019-09-16T15:30:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:31:27+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/xylitol-icing-sugar"/>
    <title>Xylitol icing sugar</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/icing-sugar-pic-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678375808" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>We regularly get emailed by people asking us if we sell xylitol 'icing sugar'. The answer is unfortunately 'no', as it's too expensive to produce commercially. It is however super easy to make yourself at home - click<span> </span><a href="http://wallflowerkitchen.com/powdered-xylitol/?fbclid=IwAR0AUN5I7vidnyupPXcFf2h9xzHnM_L-r2SwbG5ifX5lx_43laoENm0eU3k">here</a><span> </span>to discover the simple secret.</p>
<p>If there are any xylitol questions you think we might be able to help you with, please don't hesitate to<span> </span><a href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/pages/contact">contact us</a><span> </span>and we'll do our best to help. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/total-sweet-nominated-for-the-best-slimming-product</id>
    <published>2019-07-06T16:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:35:17+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/total-sweet-nominated-for-the-best-slimming-product"/>
    <title>Total Sweet nominated for the Best Slimming Product</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/total-sweet-your-healthy-living-w800_600x600.jpg?v=1678376025" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="lead">Total Sweet has been nominated for the Best Slimming Product by Your Healthy Living Magazine.</p>
<p>We're delighted that Total Sweet Xylitol has been nominated for the Best Slimming / Detox Product in the Your Healthy Living Magazine awards.</p>
<p>If you can spare a moment, please vote for us at <a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.yourhealthyliving.co.uk%2F%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR0gtRAwHC5NE55-r-VmUs2ObUgIkTuWPQbNpvGbrRONGN9N-fJF22X-eQ0&amp;h=AT0o1enk73cJBVcyFVnO0R5DuuAAJYpHrsdUkPReW562B9JcflXGlNpa1P5aD0_hX3gDBQbWe0gm-Batk51KGpUWuCxby-aHameTk5ZGJ-3vJfJl68yjNzk0k2rHzcPp5662LAkNRPeC3L2doUmM57pUPuw7MIIjLwtmvv-REFj7M2gMsz0yXh9eApuav87MDC_hxIvMnGYlqN-zYR1si8p2ounId_tOnpX8KHSipBLfeCcZkuvjOFpDcSmMLKdfkAUUPHuiTlxrc_y8lNGrNtH5mnBwkAFJVyqMXz0EVvnskcanbHHhj_AyEcqbV-BANShhQoqFZGZPhBFFNKTLtwim2_nS91350vtWaPJLs13h_n8HCyaqpOuMwiC8n809ck0C5el57GPG3kCMrscf_G3XTDce3mnBDtqTgPTdbfHiCOtHGRmRwjeucP-nAaiQKR0rhrowan5kCyD8Grnq-aMs9_Y8iunzWrMmN50sACUc5ua9L_4FyVvjEZ_G0ZiYPLve4JhQcfk0ecWAM3efTGX-LyyACqWVBQDz8yr9p_avylvUwhnSxjbWYUCWu38cbMwmtCz25p0xy9dTcRqCpugdjzz5bOZHrClt07idBqY5qCMpzm7rZR8Y3e2zpMJxSg" target="_blank" data-ft='{"tn":"-U"}' rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-lynx-mode="async">www.yourhealthyliving.co.uk</a></p>
<p>Thank you</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/your-healthy-living-2-1-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678376060" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/stacey-hart-and-sugar-free-baking</id>
    <published>2019-05-23T16:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-09T15:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.totalsweet.co.uk/blogs/news/stacey-hart-and-sugar-free-baking"/>
    <title>Stacey Hart and sugar free baking</title>
    <author>
      <name>Elisabeth Baylis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="lead"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0555/9379/5887/files/choc-xylitol-biscuits-w555h350_600x600.jpg?v=1678376268" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p class="lead">Great British Bake Off semi-finalist, Stacey Hart is trying to go sugar free...</p>
<p>Head over to Stacey's Instagram page (<a href="http://www.instagram.com/staceydeeskitchen/">www.instagram.com/staceydeeski...</a>) for some great ideas and recipes, including these sugar free chocolate biscuits, which use xylitol instead of sugar, which Stacey has kindly shared the recipe for with us...</p>
<p> </p>
<p><b>Sugar Free Chocolate Biscuits</b></p>
<p><b>Ingredients</b></p>
<p>70g softened unsalted butter</p>
<p>60g Xylitol (processed to make it into a fine icing sugar consistency)</p>
<p>80g plain flour</p>
<p>1 ½ tablespoons cocoa powder</p>
<p>1 tsp vanilla extract</p>
<p><b>Method</b></p>
<p>·         In a stand mixer with a paddle attachment mix the butter and xylitol until light in colour (1-2 mins)</p>
<p>·         Add the vanilla and mix again</p>
<p>·         Add the cocoa powder and flour and mix until just combined (if you overmix, the biscuits will become tough)</p>
<p>·         Turn out onto a clean surface and pat the mix together into a disk</p>
<p>·         Using a rolling pin roll the biscuits out to around 3 mm thick and use a cookie cutter to create the shape of your choice (Lightly dust the surface with flour to stop any sticking)</p>
<p>·         If you like you can make some holes on the top of the biscuit with a fork to add interest (this is not compulsory!)</p>
<p>·         Place the biscuits on a baking tray</p>
<p>·         Bake for 8-9 mins (watch you don't burn them)</p>
<p>·         Leave to cool on the baking tray</p>
<p>·         Store in an airtight container and eat within 3 days</p>
<p>NB. I use a coffee grinder to grind my xylitol. These are quite inexpensive and can be purchased easily</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
